<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xml" href="/classes/motion-design/feed.xslt.xml"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="/classes/motion-design/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="/classes/motion-design/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2017-12-11T14:40:30-05:00</updated><id>/classes/motion-design/</id><title type="html">Motion Design</title><subtitle>Motion design class materials and learning resources for students at Rutgers University-Newark.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Climate Change Data for Project 4</title><link href="/classes/motion-design/assignments/climate-change-data-for-project-4/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Climate Change Data for Project 4" /><published>2017-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-04T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/classes/motion-design/assignments/climate-change-data-for-project-4</id><content type="html" xml:base="/classes/motion-design/assignments/climate-change-data-for-project-4/">&lt;p&gt;Feel free (though NOT required) to add to this with any other well-sourced, well-researched information of your own, or to rephrase the content provided below (so long as the information itself is not misrepresented).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;how-it-works&quot;&gt;How it works&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Greenhouse gases act like a blanket around Earth, trapping energy in the atmosphere and causing it to warm. This phenomenon is called the greenhouse effect and is natural and necessary to support life on Earth. However, the buildup of greenhouse gases can change Earth’s climate and result in dangerous effects to human health and welfare and to ecosystems.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/climate-change-basic-information&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/climate-change-basic-information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Greenhouse gases include carbon dioxide, methane and water vapor.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nwf.org/Eco-Schools-USA/Become-an-Eco-School/Pathways/Climate-Change/Facts.aspx&quot;&gt;www.nwf.org/Eco-Schools-USA/Become-an-Eco-School/Pathways/Climate-Change/Facts.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Burning one gallon of gasoline puts 19.64 pounds of carbon dioxide into the atmosphere.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nwf.org/Eco-Schools-USA/Become-an-Eco-School/Pathways/Climate-Change/Facts.aspx&quot;&gt;www.nwf.org/Eco-Schools-USA/Become-an-Eco-School/Pathways/Climate-Change/Facts.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scientists have known since the 1800s that greenhouse gases trap heat, preventing it from escaping to space. The warming effect of greenhouse gases is amplified by feedbacks, especially from water vapor (a powerful and plentiful natural greenhouse gas), leading to more warming and changes in climate.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The atmospheric concentration of carbon dioxide (CO2) has increased by more than 40% since pre-industrial times, and the current CO2 level is higher than it has been in at least 800,000 years.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Natural influences on climate, such as changes in solar radiation, natural cycles, volcanic eruptions, and the climate’s normal year-to-year variability, can’t fully explain the current warming trend. The climate changes observed in recent decades follow a number of patterns—such as cooling at high altitudes and more warming at night than during the day—that are consistent with what scientists would expect from an increase in greenhouse gases rather than changes in solar variability or other natural causes.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sea level rise is caused primarily by two factors related to climate change: the added water from melting land ice and the expansion of sea water as it warms.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://climate.nasa.gov/vital-signs/sea-level/&quot;&gt;climate.nasa.gov/vital-signs/sea-level/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;global-outcomes&quot;&gt;Global outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;8&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2016 was the warmest year on record, continuing a decades-long warming trend in global surface temperature.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://climate.nasa.gov/vital-signs/global-temperature/&quot;&gt;climate.nasa.gov/vital-signs/global-temperature/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Earth’s 2016 surface temperatures were the warmest since modern record-keeping began in 1880, according to independent analyses by NASA and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA).&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://climate.nasa.gov/news/2537/nasa-noaa-data-show-2016-warmest-year-on-record-globally/&quot;&gt;climate.nasa.gov/news/2537/nasa-noaa-data-show-2016-warmest-year-on-record-globally/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2016 was the third year in a row to set a new record for global average surface temperatures.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://climate.nasa.gov/news/2537/nasa-noaa-data-show-2016-warmest-year-on-record-globally/&quot;&gt;climate.nasa.gov/news/2537/nasa-noaa-data-show-2016-warmest-year-on-record-globally/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The 2016 temperatures continue a long-term warming trend, according to analyses by scientists at NASA’s Goddard Institute for Space Studies (GISS) in New York. NOAA scientists concur with the finding that 2016 was the warmest year on record based on separate, independent analyses of the data.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://climate.nasa.gov/news/2537/nasa-noaa-data-show-2016-warmest-year-on-record-globally/&quot;&gt;climate.nasa.gov/news/2537/nasa-noaa-data-show-2016-warmest-year-on-record-globally/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Earth’s average temperature has risen by 1.5°F over the past century, and climate scientists estimate it will rise another 0.5 to 8.6°F by the end of this century, depending, in part, on future emissions. Small changes in the average temperature of the planet can translate to large and potentially dangerous shifts in climate and weather.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/climate-change-basic-information&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/climate-change-basic-information&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The global average temperature during the height of the last ice age was only 5 to 9°F cooler than it is today.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Over the past century, human activities have released large amounts of carbon dioxide and other greenhouse gases into the atmosphere. The majority of greenhouse gases come from burning fossil fuels to produce energy, although deforestation, industrial processes, and some agricultural practices also emit gases into the atmosphere.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/climate-change-basic-information&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/climate-change-basic-information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rising global temperatures have been accompanied by changes in weather and climate such as changes in rainfall, resulting in more floods, droughts, or intense rain, as well as more frequent and severe heat waves.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/climate-change-basic-information&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/climate-change-basic-information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Climate change has caused the planet’s oceans and glaciers to experience some big changes – oceans are warming and becoming more acidic, ice caps are melting, and sea levels are rising.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/climate-change-basic-information&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/climate-change-basic-information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;NASA’s latest satellite observations show global average sea level rising currently at 3.4 mm per year. It has risen 8 inches since 1880; it is projected to rise another 1 to 4 feet by 2100.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://climate.nasa.gov/vital-signs/sea-level/&quot;&gt;climate.nasa.gov/vital-signs/sea-level/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Especially dramatic changes are underway in the Arctic, where warming is amplified by powerful feedbacks. Reductions in sea ice, land-based ice, and snow cover, along with the thawing of permafrost, are having profound impacts in the Arctic and beyond.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rising sea levels, caused mainly by the expansion of seawater as it warms, along with billions of tons of water added to the ocean each year from melting glaciers, ice caps, and ice sheets, are affecting coastal communities in many parts of the world, including places like South Florida, Chesapeake Bay, and low-lying communities along the Gulf Coast in the United States.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Climate change is increasing our exposure to extreme temperatures, extreme weather events; degraded air quality; diseases transmitted through food, water, and insects; and stresses to mental health and well-being. These threats to human health are expected to increase with continued climate change.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The United States is the second largest contributor to CO2 in our atmosphere, though it is home to just 4.4 percent of the world’s population. If everyone in the world lived the way people do in the U.S., it would take four Earths to provide enough resources for everyone.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nwf.org/Eco-Schools-USA/Become-an-Eco-School/Pathways/Climate-Change/Facts.aspx&quot;&gt;www.nwf.org/Eco-Schools-USA/Become-an-Eco-School/Pathways/Climate-Change/Facts.aspx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.worldatlas.com/&quot;&gt;www.worldatlas.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.census.gov/popclock/&quot;&gt;www.census.gov/popclock/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.popsci.com/environment&quot;&gt;www.popsci.com/environment&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The amount of carbon dioxide emitted per capita in the United States is 16.4 metric tons (almost 40 pounds per person).&lt;br /&gt;
Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nwf.org/Eco-Schools-USA/Become-an-Eco-School/Pathways/Climate-Change/Facts.aspx&quot;&gt;www.nwf.org/Eco-Schools-USA/Become-an-Eco-School/Pathways/Climate-Change/Facts.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://databank.worldbank.org/data&quot;&gt;databank.worldbank.org/data&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The current pace of global average temperature rise puts approximately 25-35% of plant and animal species at increased risk of extinction.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nwf.org/Eco-Schools-USA/Become-an-Eco-School/Pathways/Climate-Change/Facts.aspx&quot;&gt;www.nwf.org/Eco-Schools-USA/Become-an-Eco-School/Pathways/Climate-Change/Facts.aspx&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;local-outcomes&quot;&gt;Local outcomes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol start=&quot;24&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Jersey has warmed by about 3°F in the last century. This and other climate impacts, like more intense rainfall, mean increasing risks to health. Hurricanes and storms like nor’easters may become more intense in New Jersey as the climate continues to warm.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climate-impacts/climate-change-and-human-health-risks-your-state&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climate-impacts/climate-change-and-human-health-risks-your-state&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Jersey has warmed by about 3°F in the last century. This and other climate impacts, like more intense rainfall, mean increasing risks to health. Higher temperatures and other weather changes will increase levels of ozone pollution (a component of smog), increasing health risks like asthma-related hospital visits.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climate-impacts/climate-change-and-human-health-risks-your-state&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climate-impacts/climate-change-and-human-health-risks-your-state&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Jersey has warmed by about 3°F in the last century. This and other climate impacts, like more intense rainfall, mean increasing risks to health. Longer warm seasons mean that ticks carrying Lyme disease will emerge earlier in the season and move into new areas.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climate-impacts/climate-change-and-human-health-risks-your-state&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climate-impacts/climate-change-and-human-health-risks-your-state&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Heat waves have become more frequent in the United States in recent decades. Climate scientists expect the number of days with temperatures above 90°F to increase in the United States as the climate changes, especially toward the end of this century.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Higher temperatures lead to increased rates of evaporation and can lead to more rapid drying of soils. Without reductions in global greenhouse gas emissions, longer-term droughts are expected to intensify in much of the Southwest, the Great Plains, and the Southeast.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The area burned by wildfire in parts of western North America is expected to double (or more) for each 1.8°F increase in global average temperature.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Because of rising global sea levels, flooding is becoming more frequent along the U.S. coastline, especially in the Mid-Atlantic region where the land is simultaneously sinking.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&quot;&gt;www.epa.gov/climatechange/frequently-asked-questions-about-climate-change&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In 1910 Glacier National Park was home to more an estimated 150 glaciers. That number has now shrunk to 25 as of December 2016. This national park is expected to eventually lose all its glaciers.&lt;br /&gt;Source(s): &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nwf.org/Eco-Schools-USA/Become-an-Eco-School/Pathways/Climate-Change/Facts.aspx&quot;&gt;www.nwf.org/Eco-Schools-USA/Become-an-Eco-School/Pathways/Climate-Change/Facts.aspx&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nps.gov/glac/learn/education/glaciers.htm&quot;&gt;www.nps.gov/glac/learn/education/glaciers.htm&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</content><summary type="html">Information on global climate change, sourced from the Environmental Protection Agency, NASA’s Global Climate Change initiative, and the National Wildlife Federation, that you can use to construct your information design-focused motion graphic.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/classes/motion-design/images/globe.gif" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Project 4: Information in Motion</title><link href="/classes/motion-design/assignments/project-4-information-in-motion/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project 4: Information in Motion" /><published>2017-04-03T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-04-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/classes/motion-design/assignments/project-4-information-in-motion</id><content type="html" xml:base="/classes/motion-design/assignments/project-4-information-in-motion/">&lt;p&gt;This project focuses on information design in motion. Much like how motion design is well suited to convey a particularly complex or multifaceted narrative, it also has the potential to communicate complex information or data with a lot of nuance and clarity. A timely and pressing topic that lends itself to time-based information design is the science surrounding global climate change. From the Environmental Protection Agency, on climate change:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Our Earth is warming. Earth’s average temperature has risen by 1.5°F over the past century, and is projected to rise another 0.5 to 8.6°F over the next hundred years. Small changes in the average temperature of the planet can translate to large and potentially dangerous shifts in climate and weather.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Your assignment is to create an information-driven motion graphic that utilizes space, time, motion, and sound to communicate a message about climate change.&lt;/strong&gt; This motion graphic can incorporate data, typography, imagery, icons, charts / graphs, etc., and should include an audio component of your choosing. You should use a minimum of 2-3 of the climate change facts provided to construct a thoughtful narrative / progression (feel free to rewrite or rephrase these facts as needed to achieve whatever tone is appropriate for your chosen audience). Define a particular audience for this motion graphic — &lt;em&gt;who would benefit from knowing more about this information?&lt;/em&gt; — and consider this audience when making decisions about how to communicate the information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two different but related possible approaches to time-based information design:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Animated Data Visualization&lt;/strong&gt;: this approach focuses on communicating complex data and the visual communication of information. As with all time-based media there is a narrative, but this narrative is more of a simple progression than a developed story.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Infographic-Based Narrative in Motion&lt;/strong&gt;: this approach does communicate facts, data, and information, but this information serves to develop a more complex narrative and tell a story.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As is often the case with different ways to practice design, it is very possible for there to be some overlap between these two approaches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;objectives&quot;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create an information-driven motion graphic that clearly and compellingly communicates a message&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Define and consider a specific audience for your motion graphic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thoughtfully integrate typography, imagery (representational form and/or abstract form), audio, and motion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to investigate the combination of &lt;em&gt;traditional&lt;/em&gt; design attributes (color, composition, shape, depth, tension, contrast) and &lt;em&gt;time-based&lt;/em&gt; attributes (progression, pacing, rhythm, sequence, velocity, kinetic behavior)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to investigate the development of a narrative arc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to investigate typography in motion: &lt;em&gt;traditional&lt;/em&gt; typographic characteristics (typeface, type size, kerning, tracking, leading, etc.) in addition to kinetic characteristics (motion typography and fluid typography)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to develop an advanced and complex relationship between audio and moving visual elements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show a high level of technical proficiency and skill in using After Effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;schedule--process&quot;&gt;Schedule / Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Goal&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;4/3 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project intro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;4/5 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech demo / studio work time&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Have read &lt;em&gt;Bubbles, Lines, and String: How Information Visualization Shapes Society&lt;/em&gt; by Peter Hall (&lt;a href=&quot;/classes/motion-design/resources/bubbles-lines-and-string-phall.pdf&quot;&gt;download here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;Have reviewed all provided climate change information and begun to select facts/construct narrative(s). &lt;a href=&quot;/classes/motion-design/assignments/climate-change-data-for-project-4/&quot;&gt;Data post here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;4/10 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group critique storyboards&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Storyboards for 3 distinct concepts. (&lt;em&gt;The number of frames per storyboard will vary, but most will likely average 6-10 frames per storyboard concept.&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;Selected audio to accompany your storyboard concepts (you may want to propose different audio tracks to accompany different concepts, though this is not required)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;4/12 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Studio work time&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Select the concept that you wish to move forward with and develop 3-4 key frame digital sketches for it (consider color, typography, visual language, compositions, etc).&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Key frames are sketches generally done on the computer that represent a specific point in time in the animation, and should be slightly more fully visualized in terms of the design than the initial storyboards.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;4/17 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group critique&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: First draft of your motion graphic&lt;br /&gt;Revised key frames (as needed) based on in-class feedback&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;4/19 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Studio work time&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Revised draft&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;4/24 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small group critiques&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Revised draft. (&lt;em&gt;Your draft should be at or near its full 20(ish) second length&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;4/26 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Studio work time&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Revised draft. (&lt;em&gt;Your draft must be at its full 20(ish) second length&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;5/1 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project due&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-deliverables&quot;&gt;Project deliverables&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Final time-based motion graphic
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Composition size: 1280 x 720&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Duration: approximately 20 seconds long&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drawn storyboards (for 3 concepts)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3-4 key frames (for selected concept)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rough drafts (as uploaded to Vimeo for each in-progress critique)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/classes/motion-design/resources/bubbles-lines-and-string-phall.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bubbles, Lines, and String: How Information Visualization Shapes Society&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Peter Hall&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video tutorials&lt;/strong&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynda.com/After-Effects-tutorials/After-Effects-Guru-Animating-Infographics/397611-2.html&quot;&gt;Lynda.com - Animating Infographics&lt;/a&gt; : Specifically Chapter 1 (Preparing Files for Animation) and Chapter 2 (Animating Single Infographic Elements with After Effects)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Some short(er), specific tutorials that cover different information visualization techniques (&lt;em&gt;note that these are not necessarily the only ways to make these forms&lt;/em&gt;)
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0FMCQKUF0Mg&quot;&gt;Animated pie chart&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=baGCfPyVc4Q&quot;&gt;Animated counting numbers&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cgi.tutsplus.com/tutorials/how-to-create-infographics-that-animate-themselves--ae-26627&quot;&gt;Using After Effects Expressions for infographics (general)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.meta-chart.com/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meta-Chart&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: You can use lots of programs to make charts and graphs (various Microsoft Office programs or Adobe Illustrator), and this site is another option. The resulting charts may not be beautiful but will be proportionate, so they could be used as a reference/resource to make sure your data is accurately interpreted and visualized.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.informationisbeautiful.net/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Information is Beautiful&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: An online resource that shows many varied, beautiful, and successful approaches to visualizing knowledge.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/classes/motion-design/resources/technical-resources/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;/classes/motion-design/resources/resources-for-storyboarding/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources for Storyboarding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><summary type="html">Graphic design is frequently used to interpret, to persuade, or to sell things—products, services, ideas—but it also has the capacity to spread knowledge and bring clarity to complex topics. Information design is the practice of visually presenting information so that it can be understood thoroughly and efficiently, and through this sort of practice designers can embrace the potential civic value of their work. Information design can be, at its best, a public service. Designers have a unique ability to clarify and share important information with an audience to whom this knowledge might be essential.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/classes/motion-design/images/oild.gif" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Project 3: The Reaction Gif</title><link href="/classes/motion-design/assignments/project-3-the-reaction-gif/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project 3: The Reaction Gif" /><published>2017-03-21T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2017-03-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>/classes/motion-design/assignments/project-3-the-reaction-gif</id><content type="html" xml:base="/classes/motion-design/assignments/project-3-the-reaction-gif/">&lt;p&gt;Animated GIFs are not a medium that generally involves a long, laborious design process. Part of what makes them interesting and unique is that both the concept development and the actual act of making is often quick and rough, as well as exceptionally open. Making animated GIFs is not something limited to &lt;em&gt;professional&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;serious&lt;/em&gt; designers, and they have opened the world of visual communication and motion design to many people. Anyone with access to a computer and the internet can easily make funny, interesting, effective animated GIFs from found images or video footage, from their own original footage, or by altering/combining existing GIFs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project specifically focuses on the idea of the reaction gif. From the description of &lt;em&gt;The Reaction GIF: Moving Image as Gesture,&lt;/em&gt; an exhibition at the Museum of the Moving Image:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…over the last few years, the reaction GIF has emerged as a form for communicating with short moving images in response to, and often in lieu of, text in online forums and comment threads. These animated GIFs consist of brief loops of bodies in motion, primarily excerpted from recognizable pop culture moments, and are used to express common ideas and emotions. Understood as gestures, they can communicate more nuance and concision than their verbal translations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this project you will &lt;strong&gt;create three unique GIFs&lt;/strong&gt;. They can communicate any idea(s) or emotion(s) of your choosing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A completely original &lt;em&gt;reaction GIF&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;: you must make it entirely out of your own video footage, photography, illustration, animation, or whatever else you can come up with.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Add to&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;change&lt;/em&gt; found material&lt;/strong&gt;: start with a preexisting GIF, video, image(s), or animation and in some way alter it to communicate a specific reaction: you can add design elements, juxtapose your found material against different material, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;No constraints&lt;/em&gt; for the third gif&lt;/strong&gt;. It does not have to specifically be a reaction GIF and can be anything you’d like. Experiment!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve set up a Tumblr to which all gifs created for this project should be submitted: &lt;a href=&quot;https://rutgersgifparty.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;Rutgers GIF Party&lt;/a&gt;. Submit all completed gifs to the Tumblr before the beginning of class on Monday, March 28 so that I have time to approve the posts. &lt;strong&gt;Note Tumblr’s max GIF size&lt;/strong&gt;: no larger than &lt;strong&gt;3MB&lt;/strong&gt; and no more than &lt;strong&gt;540 pixels wide&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;objectives&quot;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investigate animated gifs as a form of time-based media / motion design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Investigate altering, remixing, and juxtaposing found media to communicate a new message&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Practice rapid concept development and making&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to investigate the combination of &lt;em&gt;traditional&lt;/em&gt; design attributes (color, composition, shape, depth, tension, contrast) and &lt;em&gt;time-based&lt;/em&gt; attributes (progression, pacing, rhythm, sequence, velocity, kinetic behavior).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;schedule--process&quot;&gt;Schedule / Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Goal&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3/27 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project intro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3/29 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech demo / studio work time&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Have read &lt;em&gt;Digital Materiality of GIFs&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;a href=&quot;http://newhive.com/shashashasha/digital-materiality-of-gifs&quot;&gt;link here&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;br /&gt;Have begun collecting material (found and original) out of which you will make your GIFs&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;4/3 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project due&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-deliverables&quot;&gt;Project deliverables&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Three unique&lt;/strong&gt; animated GIFs, uploaded to the project Tumblr
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reaction GIF made &lt;em&gt;from original material&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reaction GIF made &lt;em&gt;from altering found material&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Open GIF &lt;em&gt;(no specifications or requirements)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://newhive.com/shashashasha/digital-materiality-of-gifs&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digital Materiality of GIFs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; by Sha Hwang&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.movingimage.us/exhibitions/2014/03/12/detail/the-reaction-gif-moving-image-as-gesture/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Reaction GIF: Moving Image as Gesture&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: This is the online archive of an animated gif exhibition shown at the Museum of the Moving Image, curated by Jason Eppink.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.jasoneppink.com/we-tripped-el-hadji-diouf/?pid=645&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We Tripped El Hadji Diouf&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: Another small animated gif exhibition at the Museum of the Moving Image curated by Jason Eppink.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;GIFs on Twitter&lt;/strong&gt;:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/GIFs&quot;&gt;The Ministry of GIFs (@gifs)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/animatedtext&quot;&gt;Animated Text (@animatedtext)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/toongif&quot;&gt;Cartoon GIFs (@toongif)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><summary type="html">Animated GIFs, a file format introduced in 1987, are not new technology. Still, they've been given new life in contemporary internet culture. They are portable (due to their small file size and wide support across many platforms), accessible (easy for most internet users to find, digest, and even make themselves), and their quick, looping, bite-size format lends itself well to humor and wit. All of this makes the animated GIF a popular form of online visual communication.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/classes/motion-design/images/reaction_gif.gif" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Project 2: Kinetic Type</title><link href="/classes/motion-design/assignments/project-2-kinetic-type/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project 2: Kinetic Type" /><published>2017-02-11T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-02-11T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/classes/motion-design/assignments/project-2-kinetic-type</id><content type="html" xml:base="/classes/motion-design/assignments/project-2-kinetic-type/">&lt;p&gt;For Project 2, you will begin by finding an audio clip of a spoken quote that is of personal interest to you. This audio can be contemporary or historic, can come from a speech, a news broadcast, a movie or television show, a podcast, comedy set, poem, or book — just choose something that you’re excited to work with because both the topic and manner of speech seem interesting to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The audio should be approximately 20-40 seconds long, and should be spoken rather than sung (you will have the opportunity to use music in our final project). From your selected audio clip, you will create a kinetic piece that focuses on typography in motion and the ability of moving type to effectively and thoughtfully communicate the story being told in your audio clip. Sound and carefully considered supporting imagery will also be important in the communication of your message and evolution of your narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your finished piece should be a dynamic and unique communicative experience to which kinetic type is central. Remember to include the source/attribution of your audio clip in your piece (we will discuss this in class).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;objectives&quot;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduction to kinetic typography as a narrative tool&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Consider &lt;em&gt;traditional&lt;/em&gt; typographic characteristics (&lt;em&gt;typeface, type size, kerning, tracking, leading, etc.&lt;/em&gt;) in addition to characteristics of kinetic type (&lt;em&gt;motion typography and fluid typography&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on the visual language of typography (its relationship to and visual interpretation of the content)—not just the written language of the words themselves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to investigate the combination of &lt;em&gt;traditional&lt;/em&gt; design attributes (&lt;em&gt;color, composition, shape, depth, tension, contrast&lt;/em&gt;) and &lt;em&gt;time-based&lt;/em&gt; attributes (&lt;em&gt;progression, pacing, rhythm, sequence, velocity, kinetic behavior&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to investigate the development of a narrative arc&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop a more advanced and complex relationship between audio and moving visual elements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Continue to develop technical After Effects skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;schedule--process&quot;&gt;Schedule / Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Goal&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2/13 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project intro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2/15 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tech demo / studio work time&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Read chapter 9, &lt;em&gt;Typography in Time and Motion,&lt;/em&gt; from Typographic Design: From and Communication (PDF provided below in Resources section). &lt;br /&gt;Brainstorm audio options&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2/20 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group critique storyboards &amp;amp; key frames for 3 concepts&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Your chosen audio clip, cut to the correct length, and Storyboards for 3 distinct concepts (base all of your concepts off of your chosen audio clip). &lt;br /&gt;The number of frames per storyboard will vary depending on your audio selection, but most will likely average 8-12 frames per storyboard concept. &lt;br /&gt;Key frames for these 3 distinct concepts. &lt;br /&gt;Key frames are sketches generally done on the computer that represent a specific point in time in the animation, and should be slightly more fully visualized in terms of the design than the initial storyboards.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2/22 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small group &lt;em&gt;or&lt;/em&gt; Individual critiques &amp;amp; studio work time&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Further development of chosen design direction (present more developed storyboard and revised key frames for chosen concept based on feedback). In class: start animation in After Effects.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2/27 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group critique&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: First draft of kinetic type piece (try to get through 10-15 seconds – approximately half of your full kinetic type piece), and &lt;br /&gt;Revised key frames for chosen concept (both based on feedback)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3/1 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Studio work time&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Revised draft of kinetic type piece.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3/6 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small group critique / studio work time&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Revised kinetic type draft. Try to have your draft at its full 20-40 second length for today.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3/8 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Studio work time&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Revised kinetic type draft Your draft must be at its full 20-40 seconds by this class (ideally it was already there on Monday).&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3/11 (Sat) – 3/19 (Sun)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spring Break&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3/20 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small group critique&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Revised kinetic type draft (near final).&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3/22 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Studio work day&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Revised kinetic type draft (near final) Project.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;3/27 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project due&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-deliverables&quot;&gt;Project deliverables&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Final kinetic type motion graphic
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Composition size: 1280 x 720&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Duration: approximately 20-40 seconds in length&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drawn storyboards (for 3 concepts)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4-6 key frames (for selected concept)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rough drafts (as uploads to Vimeo for in-progress critiques)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Typographic Design&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;/classes/motion-design/typographic_design_ch9_pages.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Chapter 9: Typography in Time and Motion&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storyboard Template&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;/resources/storyboard_template.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Download PDF&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audacity&lt;/strong&gt; (free audio editing software): &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.audacityteam.org/download/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Download here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.howtogeek.com/56264/the-how-to-geek-guide-to-audio-editing-cutting-trimming-arranging/&quot;&gt;A helpful guide for basic cutting, trimming, and arranging audio in Audacity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.videocopilot.net/basic/tutorials/08.Titles/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video CoPilot Titling Part 1 Tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynda.com/After-Effects-tutorials/Kinetic-Typography-Techniques-After-Effects/123481-2.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lynda.com Kinetic Typography Tutorial&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/classes/motion-design/resources/technical-resources/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;/classes/motion-design/resources/resources-for-storyboarding/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources for Storyboarding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;categories-of-kinetic-type&quot;&gt;Categories of Kinetic Type&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Derived from Barbara Bownie’s model of temporal typography in Transforming Type.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Motion Typography&lt;/strong&gt;: in which the letterforms change position over time. Motion typography is subdivided into two subcateogories:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dynamic Layout&lt;/em&gt;: Letterforms move in relation to one another (moving away / around each other)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Scrolling Typography&lt;/em&gt;: Letterforms move as a group across a screen, in two or three dimensions&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fluid Typography&lt;/strong&gt;: in which letterforms change, morph, and evolve without necessarily changing position&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;- Note that fluid and motion typography can be applied independently or simultaneously.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><summary type="html">Typography has the potential to (literally) take on another dimension when used in motion graphics. As with our previous work, this project will explore the process of combining traditional graphic design elements (such as composition, color, shape, depth, contrast, etc.) with a specific focus on typography and the dynamic, unique communicative potential of type in motion.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/classes/motion-design/images/kinetic.gif" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Project 1: Motion Studies</title><link href="/classes/motion-design/assignments/project-1-motion-studies/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Project 1: Motion Studies" /><published>2017-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2017-01-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>/classes/motion-design/assignments/project-1-motion-studies</id><content type="html" xml:base="/classes/motion-design/assignments/project-1-motion-studies/">&lt;p&gt;For our first project, you will choose one or more of the Gestalt principles listed below (and explained more in-depth at the end of this page) and use them as a point of departure from which to develop the concept and design for a series of three short (10-15 second) motion sequences. The goal of the sequences is to communicate the selected principle, utilizing the traditional design attributes of composition, color, shape, depth, tension, and contrast, while beginning to explore time-based attributes such as pacing, rhythm, and sequence. Design elements to be incorporated are abstract shapes, letterforms, and sound—no representational forms or readable text are to be used for this project (incorporated letterforms should be treated as shapes, not as pieces of words).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As much as this project is an exercise in formal design skills an introduction to After Effects, it’s also an exercise in using a time-based media to construct a narrative. Even short, simple motion graphics without recognizable imagery or readable text have a tone and mood, a beginning, middle, and end, and the fundamental change and progression that make a narrative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gestalt-principles&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#gestalt-principles-explained&quot;&gt;Gestalt principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#figure-ground&quot;&gt;Figure/Ground&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#proximity&quot;&gt;Proximity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#similarity&quot;&gt;Similarity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#symmetry&quot;&gt;Symmetry&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#closure&quot;&gt;Closure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#continuation&quot;&gt;Continuation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;objectives&quot;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create a time-based piece that successfully utilizes both &lt;em&gt;traditional&lt;/em&gt; design attributes (color, composition, shape, depth, tension, contrast) and &lt;em&gt;time-based&lt;/em&gt; attributes.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduce time-based design attributes such as progression, pacing, rhythm, sequence, velocity and kinetic behavior&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduction to constructing a narrative arc in time and space&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduction to the &lt;em&gt;principles of animation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduce and explore effective use of music (i.e. juxtaposition of sound and image)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Introduce using After Effects as a design tool, and develop technical skills and experience&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;schedule--process&quot;&gt;Schedule / Process&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Date&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;Goal&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1/18 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project intro&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1/23 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group critique storyboards&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Select visual principle(s) and audio clips that you are interested in working with and use these selections to develop 5 sets of storyboards for 5 distinct motion study concepts – sketched by hand. (You should be creating 5 sheets/pages (each 11”x17”) of sketches of design concepts for your selected Gestalt principle.) The exact number of frames per storyboard depends on what is needed for your individual concept and will vary, but overall, since these animations are short, they should only require a few frames each (approximately 4-8 frames per storyboard).&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1/25 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Studio work time and tech demo&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Select the 3 storyboard concepts that you wish to move forward with and develop 3-4 key frames for each. Key frames are sketches generally done on the computer that represent a specific point in time in the animation, and should be slightly more fully visualized in terms of the design than the initial storyboards. Also, watch the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.videocopilot.net/basic/tutorials/01.Introduction/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;VideoCoPilot After Effects Basic Training 01: Introduction tutorial&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; before this class to prepare you for our in-class tech demo.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;1/30 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group critique&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: First draft of motion study animations. Have started animating at least 2, if not all 3, of your motion studies in After Effects. Get through as much of the 10-15 seconds per sequence as possible, but the focus should be on the quality of animation rather than the duration. Make sure to upload your in-progress drafts to Vimeo and post them to our group before class starts (leave a some time for this upload process!). &lt;br /&gt;If, as you’re working, you feel that need additional practice or a refresher on what was covered during the our first tech demo, watch &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.videocopilot.net/basic/tutorials/03.Animation/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;VideoCoPilot After Effects Basic Training 03: Animation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. It covers much of what we will have learned in class.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2/1 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Studio work time / individual or small group critiques&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Revised motion study animations. If you hadn’t started all 3 motion studies for Monday’s class, have the third animation started by this class. It’s ok if you haven’t yet managed to make revisions addressing all feedback from Monday’s class, but still try to have made some substantial progress. &lt;br /&gt;Make sure to upload your in-progress drafts to Vimeo and post them to our group before class starts (leave a some time for this upload process!).&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2/6 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Small group critiques&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Revised motion study animations. All sequences should be animated to their full 10-15 second length.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2/8 (Wed)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group critique&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Due this class&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Revised motion study animations. Try to have them as close to final as possible!&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;2/13 (Mon)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: left&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Project due&lt;/strong&gt;. / Intro Project 2&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;project-deliverables&quot;&gt;Project deliverables&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drawn Storyboards for 5 concepts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Digital key frames for 3 concepts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Three 10-15 second long animations*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Please do not delete in-process drafts of your final project as you revise the project and upload newer versions! I will use the in-process animations to evaluate the progress that you’ve made while working on the project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;resources&quot;&gt;Resources&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio Files&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;/classes/motion-design/resources/project1_audio.zip&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Download starter audio files&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;If you would prefer to find / use your own 10-15 second clips of audio (no vocals) feel free! Otherwise, these are here for you to choose from.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Storyboard Template&lt;/strong&gt;: &lt;a href=&quot;/classes/motion-design/resources/storyboard_template.pdf&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Download PDF&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;It’s fine to make your own storyboards instead of printing and using this template, but if you do: &lt;em&gt;make sure that to work in 16:9&lt;/em&gt; proportioned frames, and keep in mind that this will have to be pinned to the wall and critiqued by the group next class.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;After Effects 101 Tutorials&lt;/strong&gt;: (&lt;em&gt;links below&lt;/em&gt;)
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.videocopilot.net/basic/tutorials/01.Introduction/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Intro&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.videocopilot.net/basic/tutorials/02.Effects/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Effects&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.videocopilot.net/basic/tutorials/03.Animation/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Animation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.videocopilot.net/basic/tutorials/10.Rendering/&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rendering&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lynda.com/After-Effects-tutorials/After-Effects-CC-Essential-Training-2015/371399-2.html&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lynda.com AE Essential Training (2015)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: These are more in-depth video tutorials than the above After Effects 101 videos. Longer, but also very informative.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/classes/motion-design/resources/technical-resources/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Resources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&quot;/classes/motion-design/resources/resources-for-storyboarding/&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resources for Storyboarding&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;gestalt-principles-explained&quot;&gt;Gestalt principles explained&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gestalt psychology, developed in the 1920s by German psychologists, is about perception and grouping. The gestalt principles below describe ways that people tend to subconsciously organize visual elements into groups when these elements are arranged in certain ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;figure-ground&quot;&gt;Figure-Ground&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The relationship between a perceived object (figure) and the perceived space (ground) that it exists in. Our perception of what is figure and what is ground is not absolute—the relationship of visual elements can cause it to shift.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;proximity&quot;&gt;Proximity&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Objects placed close together are often perceived as a group, rather than as separate shapes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;similarity&quot;&gt;Similarity&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Objects that look or act similar to one another are often perceived as a group.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;symmetry&quot;&gt;Symmetry&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When objects are arranged in a balanced composition, they are often perceived as a whole rather than individually.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;closure&quot;&gt;Closure&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;People have a tendency to fill in missing information in order to perceive an object as whole. If enough of a shape is indicated, it can be perceived as whole if incomplete or not fully enclosed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;continuation&quot;&gt;Continuation&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When a viewer’s eye is compelled to follow a path from one object to another, or to follow a certain pattern of motion through time, the individual objects are perceived as a group.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you feel you need further explanation of Gestalt, the following resources are helpful:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://graphicdesign.spokanefalls.edu/tutorials/process/gestaltprinciples/gestaltprinc.htm&quot;&gt;The Gestalt Principles&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.users.totalise.co.uk/~kbroom/Lectures/gestalt.htm&quot;&gt;Gestalt Theory of Visual Perception&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><summary type="html">For our first project, you will choose one or more of the Gestalt principles and use them as a point of departure from which to develop the concept and design for a series of three short (10-15 second) motion sequences.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="/classes/motion-design/images/dot_line_gifA.gif" /></entry></feed>
